

Terence Irudhaya Raj <u>terencemarsh6@gmail.com</u> +91 9962090893 Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

A well qualified Full-Stack Developer specialized in programming design, development, and implementation of functional specifications. Implementing scalable web-applications using modern technologies and popular frameworks such as React.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS and Javascript are the areas of my interest. Strong analytical skills with a keen eye for detail and ability to rapidly learn and adapt to new technologies. Also, possess excellent communication skills and teamwork abilities to contribute to efficient project management and successful software solutions.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## • Tele Calling Executive American Express

January 2019 - July 2019

Assisted the customer in product related queries, found the right solutions within brief moments.

## CSP

#### Sitel

March 2021 - Feb 2023

Held responsible to call up the customers who were already interested in the product and had to describe how it would be profitable to them

## **EDUCATION**

St.Mary's Anglo Indian Higher Secondary School, Chennai, India (SSLC)

June 2010 - May 2011

St.Mary's Anglo Indian Higher Secondary School, Chennai, India (HSC)

June 2013 - May 2014

Sathyabama Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, India (Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering)

June 2014 - April 2018

## PROJECTS & WORKSHOPS

#### **ACADEMIC PROJ ECT**

 Experimental Analysis of an Innovative Dual Axis Tracking Linear Fresnel lens Concentrated Solar Thermal Collector (2 months). This project is mainly aimed at developing the concept of generating steam in short span from solar energy. The steam could be used in a number of applications like thermal power plants, cooking, wood treatment, etc.

## SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Specialized and Proficient in front-end development
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- React.js
- Node.js
- Express.js
- SOL
- MongoDB

## PROJECTS & WORKSHOPS

#### **INDUSTRIAL VISIT**

 To enhance my industrial knowledge, I have made a 1-day industrial Visit to Shakthi Industries

#### **WORKSHOP ATTENDED**

- Participated in the two-day National Workshop on Challenge and Innovative in Welding technology conducted 6y Sathya6ama University.
- Attended Technical Quiz Conducted at "Gasolina 2k16", a National Level Technical Symposium that was held at AC Tech Anna University, Chennai between 26 to 28th Feb 2016.

## SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Bootstrap
- Proficient in English Communication:
  Written, Verbal, Listening and E-mail writing
- Microsoft: Office Suite, Word, PowerPoint, Excel.
- Skilled in building customer relationships.
- Critical thinking and Problem Solving
- Target oriented, Inter-Personal skills and Detail - oriented.
- Organizational and Time Management.
- Multi-task, Learn new skills and Analyze complex information.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Full Stack Development Course (6 months)
- IELTS Scored an overall of 6.5 Band in IELTS.
- Certificate for completing 2-days In Plant training at Ashok Leyland
- Certificate for participating in Gasolina 2k16 at Anna University from Feb 2016 to Jun 2016

## **EXTRACURRICULARS**

- Powerlifting
- Playing basketball and volleyball

## HARD SKILLS

- PRINCIPLES OF MANAGEMENT
- TOTAL QUALITY OF MANAGEMENT
- ADAPTABILITY
- INDUSTRIAL MANUFACTURING

## LANGUAGES KNOWN

- English (Proficient in writing, reading, speaking and writing)
- Tamil (Proficient in writing, reading, speaking and writing)

# </SOFTWARE ENGINEER>